

2244 West Taylor Street. Fl. 1. Chicago, IL 60612, United States

□ (+1) 312-478-1131 | 🗷 abose4@uic.edu | 🌴 www.arindambose.com | 🖸 arindam-bose | 🛅 arindam-bose-75425417

Summary

Currently a Ph.D. candidate at Electrical and Computer Engineering Department, University of Illinois at Chicago and a research assistant at WaveOPT lab under Prof. Mojtaba Soltanalian. Research interests include signal processing and optimization theory, radar signal processing, active sensing, and theory of machine learning. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies.

Work Experience _____

KMB Telematics Arlington, VA, USA

SUMMER INTERN, FMCW RADAR DESIGN LAB

May 2019 - Aug. 2019

Developed efficient algorithms for designing antennas for FMCW automotive radar

Mitsubishi Electric Research Laboratories

Cambridge, MA, USA

SUMMER INTERN, TERAHERTZ IMAGING LAB

May 2018 - Aug. 2018

Developed several efficient model based and machine learning algorithms for Time-Domain Spectroscopy systems using THz

University of Illinois at Chicago

Chicago, IL, USA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, WAVEOPT LAB, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Jul. 2016 - PRESENT

- · Developing several non-convex optimization algorithms for waveform design for smart active sensing systems
- Assisting and collaborating with Dr. M. Soltanalian in signal processing and optimization theory research and working towards PhD thesis

TEACHING ASSISTANT, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING AND DEPARTMENT OF PHYSICS

Aug. 2015 - PRESENT

- Courses assisted: Digital signal processing, Statistical signal processing, Image analysis and computer vision, Introductory physics, General physics
- Collaborated with several professors to setup exam questions and answers
- · Graded papers, conducted lab sessions, and proctored examinations

Cognizant Technology Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Kolkata, India

PROGRAMMER ANALYST, HEALTH CARE PRACTICE

Aug. 2014 - Apr. 2016

- Developed and maintained several Java based web projects according to client requests
- Designed web services and complex web pages in JSP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Maintained PI and other health related client data in complex Oracle databases
- Developed and delivered special projects: Log Parser a log management system for complex bug reports, PBMAid an android app to track insurance related data for patients

Major Publications

JOURNAL PAPERS

Joint Optimization of Waveform Covariance Matrix and Antenna Selection for MIMO Radar with an Application to Aerial Drones

A. Bose, S. Khobahi, and M. Soltanalian
Submitted in IEEE Transactions on Aerospace and Electronic Systems

2020

One-Bit Radar Processing With Time-Varying Sampling Thresholds

2019

· Published in IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing

Constructing Binary Sequences With Good Correlation Properties: An Efficient Analytical-Computational Interplay

A. BOSE, M. SOLTANALIAN

• Published in IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

S. KHOBAHI, A. BOSE, AND M. SOLTANALIAN

A. Ameri, A. Bose, J. Li, and M. Soltanalian

Deep One-Bit Compressive Autoencoder

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

July 2020

• Submitted in IEEE Statistical Signal Processing Workshop (SSP) 2020

FEBRUARY 24, 2020 ARINDAM BOSE · RÉSUMÉ

Deep-URL: A Model-Aware Approach to Blind Deconvolution Based on Deep Unfolded **Richardson-Lucy Network**

Abu Dhabi, UAE

October 2020

Nov. 2019

Nov. 2019

Sep. 2019

Sep. 2019

Jun. 2019

Nov. 2018

Apr. 2018

Kolkata, India

2008 - 2012

Anaheim, CA, USA

Calgary, AB, Canada

Paris, France

C. AGARWAL, S. KHOBAHI, A. BOSE, M. SOLTANALIAN, AND D. SCHONFELD

• Submitted in IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP) 2020

Deep Radar Waveform Design for Efficient Automotive Radar Sensing

Hangzhou, China S. KHOBAHI, A. BOSE, AND M. SOLTANALIAN Jun. 2020

• Submitted in IEEE Sensor Array and Multichannel Signal Processing Workshop (SAM) 2020

Joint Optimization of Waveform Covariance Matrix and Antenna Selection for MIMO Radar Pacific Grove, CA, USA

A. BOSE, S. KHOBAHI, AND M. SOLTANALIAN • Presented in IEEE Asilomar Conference on Signals, Systems, and Computers 2019

Waveform Design for One-Bit Radar Systems Under Uncertain Interference Statistics Pacific Grove, CA, USA

A. Ameri, A. Bose, and M. Soltanalian

• Presented in IEEE Asilomar Conference on Signals, Systems, and Computers 2019

Learning-Based Shadow Mitigation for Terahertz Multi-Layer Imaging Paris, France

P. Wang, T. Koike-Akino, **A. Bose**, R. Ma, P. Orlik, W. Tsujita, K. Sadamoto, H. Tsutada, and M. Soltanalian

Presented in IEEE International Conference on Infrared, Millimeter, and Terahertz Waves (IRMMW-THz) 2019

THz Multi-Layer Imaging Via Nonlinear Inverse Scattering

A. Bose, A. Kadu, H. Mansour, P. Wang, P. Boufounos, P. Orlik, and M. Soltanalian

Presented in IEEE International Conference on Infrared, Millimeter, and Terahertz Waves (IRMMW-THz) 2019

Comprehensive Personalized Ranking Using One-Bit Comparison Data Minneapolis, MN, USA

A. Ameri, **A. Bose**, and M. Soltanalian

Presented in IEEE Data Science Workshop (DSW) 2019

Design of Unimodular Sequence Sets with Good Correlation and Complementary Correlation **Properties**

I. A. Arriaga-Trejo, A. Bose, A. G. Orozco-Lugo, and M. Soltanalian

Presented in 6th IEEE Global Conference on Signal and Information Processing (GlobalSIP) 2018, November 2018

Designing Signals with Good Correlation and Distribution Properties

A. BOSE, N. MOHAMMADI, M. SOLTANALIAN

· Presenting in 43rd IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP), April 2018

Education_

University of Illinois at Chicago Chicago, IL, USA

PHD IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING 2016 - 2020

• Thesis: Waveform synthesis for active sensing with emerging applications

· Advisor: Dr. Mojtaba Soltanalian

B.Tech in Electronics and Communication Engineering

West Bengal University of Technology

· Thesis: Efficient algorithms for digital watermarking

· Advisor: Dr. Somnath Maiti

Skills

Programming Language MATLAB, Python, C, C++, Java

Libraries PyTorch, OpenCV

Web Designing JavaScript, CSS 3, HTML 5, JSP, JQuerry, PHP

Database Management System Oracle RDBMS, MySQL, PL/SQL, SQLite

> Language English, Hindi, Bengali